Guide to the Bernard Augustine De Voto Papers, 1918-1955 (inclusive), 1944-1951 (bulk) M0001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Articles, Reviews, Speeches, Etc., Series 4
  - Articles, Literary, Subseries 4.3
    - Letter to Hans Zinsser on Taste and Fiction (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - "Three Novels of 1939,"The Atlantic, Jan, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - "The Present Status of American Fiction." -- Publication unidentified (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - The Watchful Gods and Other Stories, by Walter van Tilburg Clark, reviewed from galleys, publication unidentified (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - We Accept with Pleasure, letter of explanation unidentified (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - We Happy Few, by Helen Howe, review, NYHT Books title "When the Goths Took Harvard,", June 30, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Western Star, by Stephen Vincent Benet, title "Seed Time of the New World," NYT Books, June 27, 1943 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Hanna, Crane and the Mauve Decade, by Thomas Beer, review, NYHT Books, August 24, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Political Articles, Subseries 4.4
    - "The Ex-Communists," Atlantic, Feb., 1951 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "The Engulfed Cathedral,"Harper's, Easy Chair, Mar., 1940 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "Mathiessen and the Progressive Party": letter to theHerald, April 4, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "The SAC Beneath the Fangs," proposed Easy Chair on McCarthy, unpublished (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Strange Fruit case (Box 49, Folder 5)
      A. Typescript, 3 copies -- B. "Fiction is Vicious", 3 copies -- C. Mss of work on the Strange Fruit case -- D. Five typescript notes and reviews and brief
    - "The South,"Harper's Easy Chair, November, 1944 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "University of Texas,"Harper's Easy Chair, Aug, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Castle Adamant,"Harper's, Jan, 1927 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - "A Lecture to a Woman's Club,"Harper's, Easy Chair, Feb., 1942 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Commencement address at Goddard College, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - "I Can't Quite Hear You," article in answer to Dr. Brandt, Harper's, March, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      publication unidentified
  - Articles, General, Subseries 4.5
    - "The American Highway," entitled "The American Road,"Freedom of the Road, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - "Early Highways of the East," entitled "Roads of the Past"The Lamp, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - "Esso Touring Aids Program," publication unidentified (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "Flats Fixed at Mel's Bar-B-Q," publication unidentified (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "Marco Polo's Ford,"W-Day, May, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "Men, Women and Eight Cylinders,"W-Day, Feb. 1951 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - "Night Crossing,"W-Day, Aug. 1947 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - "The Protocol of Touring," purchased by The Lamp (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - "The Railroads Lose $400," publication unidentified (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - "Roadside Meeting," W-Day, July, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - "Transcontinental Flight,"Harper's," Easy Chair, July, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - "Two Days in Washington," W-Day, March, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "Commencement Address,"Harper's, Easy Chair, July, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - "Lost Generation,"Harper's, Easy Chair, April, 1944 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - "Dead Center,"Harper's, Easy Chair, October, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - "Either--Or,"Harper's, Easy Chair, August, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - "Religious Intolerance,"Harper's, Easy Chair, August, 1944 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - "War is the Life I Live,"W-Day, December, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Washington in War Time (untitled),Harper's, Easy Chair, December, 1943 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - "The Watchers on the Walls,"W-Day, June, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - "What to Tell the Young,"Harper's," Easy Chair, May, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - "Women in the Military Services,"W-Day, June 1952 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - End of World War II, (untitled),Harper's, Easy Chair, October 1945 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - "Fair Weather Children," sold toW-Day, unpublished (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - "Topic One,"W-Day, May 1953 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - "What to Tell the Child" (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - "The Women," Women and their roles, sold to W-Day (Box 50, Folder 28)
      unpublished
    - On anti-vivesectionists, Easy Chair, June 1946 (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - "Beating the Bali Hai Racket" (Easy Chair), Jan. 1956 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - About Bud Guthrie (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - "Ce qu'il fait connaitre des cocktails Pour les hostesses" (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - "Listen Sister" by Farley Blake,Atlantic, July 1957 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - State of Union Easy Chair, September 1945 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - After ten years in the chair Easy Chair, November, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - Fishing (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - "Heavy, Heavy, What Hangs Over?"Holiday, Mar. 1956 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - "The Martini Unadorned," entitled "What Makes a Real Martini," inTrue, February 1954 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - "The Old Home We Never Wanted" "Gone Are the Days" W-Day, October 1956 (Box 50, Folder 38)
      (American Culture)
    - A salute to the Lewiston Morning Tribune (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - "Spread of an Infection" (Public Health Survey) (Easy Chair), August 1955 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - "The Point of a Needle,"Fortune, April 1957 (Box 50, Folder 41)
      (Business, advertising, etc)
    - "Why Professors are Suspicious of Business" (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - "You Too Can Talk to Geniuses,"W-Day, July 1951 (Box 50, Folder 42)
      Published as "Anyone Can Talk to a Genius"
    - Easy Chair "Victory at Sea,", June 1954 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - "The Century,"Harper's, Oct. 1950 (Box 50, Folder 44)
      About America to 1950
    - Review of The Eyes of Discovery, by John Blakeless, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 45)
      NYHT Books, November 26, 1950
    - "The Lineage of Eustace Tilley,"Saturday Review of Literature, September 25, 1937 (Box 50, Folder 46)
  - Literature, Subseries 4.6
    - no title, p.117 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - no title, pt.1 p.101 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "The Mormons", p.1 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "The River and the Idol", p.59 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Article, ca. 1919 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 1913: The Reasonableness of World Wide Conciliation (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Notes for story? (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Essays (Box 51, Folder 5)
      "What Kind of Revolution"--"Thinking About America"--"Touring New England"--Ogden and its background (no name)-- story fragment-- "Mark Twain: The Link of History"--"Mark Twain: And the Limits of Criticism"
    - College poems, 2 copies (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Literature in the American Experiment, April 1920 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Henry Adams' Dynamic Theory of History, May 1920
    - Literary Sketches, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Preface--Resurreximus--Martin Would A Fishing Go--Up from the Oyster--Sunbeams from Cucumbers--Between Quintana and The Deep Blue Sea--A Stranger Comes to the Well--There Was a Man--The Burning Bush--Suggestions to Mr. Lincoln--Chataugua and the Desert Stars--Arise, Be of Good Cheer--"La-Plata Mines to be Reppened"--The Home Town Newspaper--Misericordia--A Bus Les Rollos--A Defect of Me Slingerland's Quality--Chapter One, "In the Valley"--for a novel -- A Begger at the Gate -- While the Philistine Jostle -- An Undergraduate in Education -- A Most Useful Engine for Catching Owls -- Bowing--And the Dodging Turnips -- Untitled--about George Washington
  - Fiction, Subseries 4.7
    - "Artist in the Kitchen," entitled "My Wife is Many Cooks," Cady Hewes, April 1954 (Box 51.1, Folder 1)
    - "The Baron's Right," John August, Publication unidentified (Box 51.1, Folder 2)
    - "The Bulfinch House," John August,Harper's, July 1934 (Box 51.1, Folder 3)
    - "An Hour on Sunday," entitled "A Date for Thursday," John August,Colliers, June 12, 1937 (Box 51.1, Folder 4)
    - "The Impatient Patient," Cady Howes,W-Day, Mar. 1954 (Box 51.1, Folder 5)
    - "J-Herrod," publication unidentified (not located) (Box 51.1, Folder 6)
    - "The Trick," entitled "The Hidden," by Frank Gilbert,Esquire, July 1954 (Box 51.1, Folder 7)
    - "Over the Mountain," John August, Publication unidentified (Box 51.1, Folder 8)
    - "The Precarious Attitudes of Robeson Ballon," John August,Post, July 26, 1930 (Box 51.1, Folder 9)
    - "Sex and the Co-ed," John August, purchased by American Mercury, 1927 (Box 51.1, Folder 10)
    - "Sleeping Dogs," John August,Post, Nov. 19, 1927 (Box 51.1, Folder 11)
    - "Suspicion of Violence," John August, publication unidentified (Box 51.2, Folder 12)
    - Seven Short Story Fragments (A to G) (Box 51.2, Folder 13)
  - Speeches, Subseries 4.8
    - New York Times Book Fair, 1937 (Box 52.1, Folder 1)
    - New York Times Book Fair, 1937 (Box 52.1, Folder 1)
    - World of Tomorrow, 1939 (Box 52.1, Folder 2)
    - 3 From 1942 on the War (Box 52.1, Folder 3)
    - Democratic Campaign Speech (Box 52.1, Folder 4)
    - 2 Speeches, 1944-45 (Box 52.1, Folder 5)
    - Commencement Address, Colorado University, 1948 (Box 52.1, Folder 6)
    - Living America Series--U.S.A., 1949 (Box 52.2, Folder 7)
      (See also Container 48, no. 12, for printed version)
    - Stevenson speeches, texts and notes (Box 52.2, Folder 8)
    - "Literature and the American Historian" (Box 52.2, Folder 9)
    - "Of Men and Books" (Box 52.2, Folder 10)
    - "Censorship in Massachusetts" (Box 52.2, Folder 11)
    - Announcements of Speeches (Box 52.2, Folder 12)
    - American Fiction (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Censorship (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - "Democratic Vistas" (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Emerson--Easy Chair (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Freedom (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - "German Offensive Psychological Warfare" (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - History (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Indians (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - "Leaves from a Library Table" (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Novels (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Public Domain and Conservation (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - "Some American Symbols" (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Twain (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Mark Twain and The White Whale (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Uncle Remus (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - U.S.A (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Safeguarding our National Wealth (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - The Easy Chair--Final (Box 53, Folder 18)
      a. Accuracy--an Electronic Miracle -- b. Looking Glass Law--America
    - Parkman (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Broadcasts, Lectures and Films, Subseries 4.9
    - 3 lectures broadcast on historical fiction: I. "A Problem: The Civil War,", 1937 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 3 lectures broadcast on historical fiction: I. "A Problem: The Civil War,", 1937 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 3 lectures broadcast on historical fiction: II. "The Attitudes of Fiction,", 1937 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 3 lectures broadcast on historical fiction: III. "The Materials of History,", 1937 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Radio Program about BDV's Year of Decision: 1846, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - NY Philharmonic Intermission features, CBS, 1944 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Invitation to Learning, CBS, June 4, 1944 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Invitation to Learning, CBS, August 5, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Herald Tribune Forum, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      Conservation "Our Imperiled Resources"
    - TV, "Mesa Verde, "Adventure, November 13, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "The People's Heritage," TV films (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Harvard Phi Beta Kappa Address, "The Waste Land and the Irresponsibles" (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Lecture Notes on Writing (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Lecture notes, Subseries 4.10
    - American Fiction (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Censorship (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Democratic Vistas (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Emerson--Easy Chair (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Freedom (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - German Offensive Psychological Warfare (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - History (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Indians (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Leaves from a Library Table (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Novels (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Public Domain and Conservation (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Some American Symbols (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Twain (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Mark Twain and The White Whale (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Uncle Remus (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - U.S.A. (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Safeguarding our National Wealth (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - The Easy Chair--Final (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Parkman (Box 53, Folder 19)
- Research Material, Series 5
  - Notebooks, Subseries 5.1
    General note
    Many of the titles were Bernard DeVoto's own. Most of the material relates to historical research.
    alphabetically-arranged.
    - American Literature A-L (Box 53)
    - Conservation and Public Lands (Box 53)
    - Exploration in Trans-Mississippi Area (Box 54)
    - Frontier and West (Box 54)
    - Frontier Literature (Box 54)
    - Fur Trade A-L (Box 54)
    - Fur Trade M-Z (Box 55)
    - History and Historical Literature (Box 55)
    - Indians (Box 55)
    - Indians: Ruxton and Welsh (Box 55)
    - Lewis and Clark (Box 56)
    - Mark Twain (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
    - Personal (Box 57)
    - Utah, West (Box 57)
    - West (Box 57)
    - Alfred Miller (Box 58)
      A. Letters written by Alfred J. Miller--B. Alfred J. Miller-Notes to Indian Sketches from the the collection in the Walters Gallery.--C. From the notebook marked "Alfred J. Miller"-- D. Alfred Jacob Miller - A Neglected Baltimore Painter 1810-1874: Manuscript with Photocopies of drawings
    - Year of Decision 1846, card notes (Box 59)
    - Year of Decision 1846, manuscript notes (Box 59)
    - Other West, card notes (Box 60)
    - Small note pads, mainly for travel (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous headings, cards, notes (Box 62)
    - Manuscript notes (Box 63)
  - Research Materials, Subseries 5.2
    Includes brochures, mimeographed material, and some typescript notes.
    Arranged alphabetically by major subjects and then by folder titles.
    - Black Mountain College Case (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Book Censhorship (4) (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Book Censorship-Boston (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Forever Amber (2) (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Free Speech (2) (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - F.B.I. (Box 65.1, Folder 1)
    - Obscenity Law (Box 65.1, Folder 2)
    - Peters Case - Yale (Box 65.1, Folder 3)
    - Reece Committee (Box 65.1, Folder 4)
    - Strange Fruit (Box 65.1, Folder 5)
    - Advisory Committee on Conservation (Box 65.1, Folder 6)
    - Agricultural Resource (Box 65.1, Folder 7)
    - Anti-Forest Service Propaganda, 1953-55 (Box 65.1, Folder 8)
    - Arizona Game Association (Box 65.2, Folder 1)
    - Barret Committee (Box 65.2, Folder 2)
    - Boise National Forest Fire Plan (Box 65.2, Folder 3)
    - Cache National Forest (Box 65.2, Folder 4)
    - Citizens Committee on Natural Resources (Box 65.2, Folder 5)
    - Congress 53-55 (Box 65.2, Folder 6)
    - California Water Problem (Box 65.2, Folder 7)
    - Carpenter, Farington (Box 65.2, Folder 8)
    - Colorado River and Central Arizona Project (Box 65.2, Folder 9)
    - Colorado State Lands (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Columbia Basin (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Dinosaur National Monument, no. 1, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Dinosaur National Monument, no. 2, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Dinosaur National Monument, no. 3, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Dinosaur National Monument, no. 4, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Drought (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Ecology (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Erosion, Dustbowl (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Farm Journal (Box 67.1, Folder 1)
    - Federal Lands, Status and fiscal signifigance, notes 52-3 (Box 67.1, Folder 2)
    - Firefighting (Box 67.1, Folder 3)
    - Forest Service, 1940-5 (Box 67.1, Folder 4)
    - Forest Service, 1946 (2) (Box 67.1, Folder 5)
    - Forest Service, 1947-8 (Box 67.1, Folder 6)
    - Forest Service, 1950-2 (Box 67.1, Folder 7)
    - National Forest Recreation and Timber, 1952-54 (Box 67.1, Folder 8)
    - Forest Service, 1953 (Box 67.1, Folder 9)
    - Forest Service, 1954 (Box 67.2, Folder 1)
    - Forest Service, 1955 (Box 67.2, Folder 2)
    - Publicity and Organization (Box 67.2, Folder 3)
    - Forest Service Research (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Forest Service Research (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - School Forests (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - School Forests (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - State Payments and Lands (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - State Payments and Lands (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Grand Mesa (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Grazing (2) (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Grazing and Forests, 1948 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Grazing and Land Grab (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Grazing, 1951 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Grazing Service (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Green Mountain National Forest Trip (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Hells Canyon (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Hoover Dam (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Land Grab, 1940-5 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Land Grab, 1946-7 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Land Grab, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Land Grab Clippings (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Massachusetts Forests (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Mining claims on Public Lands (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Missouri River Basin (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - National Highway Program (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - National Parks Advisory Board (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - National Parks Advisory Board, 1940's (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - National Parks Advisory Board, 1950 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - National Parks Advisory Board, 1951 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - National Parks Advisory Board, 1952-4 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - National Parks Advisory Board, 1955 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - New England (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - North Africa Water Conserve (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Parkways (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Parkways Report (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Public Lands Conservation, 1938-46 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Public Lands Conservation, 1946-7 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Public Lands Conservation, 1948-51 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Public Lands Conservation, 1952 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Public Lands Conservation, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Chart of Conservation, 1849-1949 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Public Lands, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Public Lands, 1955 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Public Lands, Report (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Public Power (2) (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Ranch Lands in Ancient Italy (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Range War, 1948 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Reclamation, 1950 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Reclamation-miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - TVA, 1950's (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Reclamation Projects (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Utah economy and resources (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Stevenson campaign conservation material (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Utah floods (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Stockmen (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Stream Pollution (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Tidelands oil issue, 1953 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Timber (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Tourists in National Parks (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Tourist slums (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Utah water control (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Velie (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Wasatch (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Wilderness (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Wildlife Management Institute (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Two miscellaneous reports by Benson and McKay (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Wichita National Wildlife Refuge Controversy, (1955) (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - People, Subseries 5.3
    - Thomas Carlyle -- (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Ray Chandler -- (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Norman Corwin -- (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - James Gould Cozzens -- (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Hart Crane -- (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - John Dos Passos -- (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Newton B. Drury -- (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - James T. Farrell -- (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - William Faulkner -- (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Robert Frost -- (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Ernest Hemingway -- (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - James Jones -- (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Sinclair Lewis -- (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Vachel Lindsay -- (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Douglas MacKay -- (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Archibald Macleish -- (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - McCarthy, Senator Joseph R-- (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - A.J. Miller (2) (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Mark Twain - 1 (Box 73)
    - Wayne Morse -- (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Richard Neuberger -- (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Eugene O'Neill -- (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Wilfredo Pareto -- (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Ezra Pound -- 5/12 Fletcher Pratt -- (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Eugene M. Rhodes -- (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr. -- (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Mickey Spillane -- (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Harold Stearns -- (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Gertrade Stein -- (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - John Steinbeck -- (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Rex Stout -- (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Dr. Robert Toft -- (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - William Carlos Williams -- (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Harry L. Wilson -- (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Thomas Wolfe -- (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Mark Twain - 2 (Box 74)
  - West and Frontier, Subseries 5.4
    - Miscellaneous photostat copies of St. Louis wholesale prices, 1833-34 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      --
    - Calamity Jane -- (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Chouteau Papers Lucien Fontenelle: Death & Burial (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Forts: Bernard, Platte, Laramie -- (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - General Ashley, The Overland Trail and South Pass (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Gilpen, William (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Indians (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Indians Beckworth -- (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Indians Warren -- (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Journal of Peregine Sessions (Box 75.1, Folder 1)
    - Journal of a Trapper (Box 75.1, Folder 2)
    - Journal of William H. Gray (Box 75.1, Folder 3)
    - Journey to the Rocky Mountains (Box 75.1, Folder 4)
    - Letters of Daniel T. Potts (Box 75.1, Folder 5)
    - Life in the Far West - Ruxton - Chapter 2 (Box 75.1, Folder 6)
    - Life in the Far West - Ruxton - Chapter 8 (Box 75.1, Folder 7)
    - Life of Norton Jacob (Box 75.2, Folder 1)
    - Supply Record - California Battalion, ce 1846 (Box 75.2, Folder 2)
    - Two Early Maps - West & U.S. (Box 75.2, Folder 3)
    - Medical and Philosophical News, 1804-1807 (Box 75.2, Folder 4)
    - Mining (Box 75.2, Folder 5)
    - Mormons - 1 (Box 75.2, Folder 6)
    - Mormons - 2 (Box 75.2, Folder 7)
    - Mormons - Joseph Smith (Box 75.2, Folder 8)
    - PS Ogden, journal excerpts (Box 75.2, Folder 9)
    - Oregon Question (Box 75.2, Folder 10)
    - Photostats, miscellaneous - 1 (Box 75.2, Folder 11)
    - Photostats, miscellaneous - 2 (Box 75.2, Folder 12)
    - Parkman letters (Box 75.2, Folder 13)
    - Photostats, miscellaneous - 3 (Box 75.2, Folder 13)
    - Parkman notes (Box 75.2, Folder 14)
    - Pony Express (Box 75.2, Folder 15)
    - San Francisco in, 1850 (Box 75.2, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper photostats on Gold Rush; Sutters Mill -, 1873, 1878 (Box 75.2, Folder 17)
    - Wah-To-Yah / L.H. Garrard (Box 76.1, Folder 1)
    - Zenas Leonard's Narrative -- (Box 76.1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellany, Subseries 5.5
    - American Medical Association (Box 76.1, Folder 3)
    - American Trails Association -- (Box 76.1, Folder 4)
    - Astronomy (Box 76.1, Folder 5)
    - Emigration to the Tropical World-Etzler (Box 76.1, Folder 6)
    - History of North African Campaign (Box 76.1, Folder 7)
    - Indian Affairs - Current (Box 76.1, Folder 8)
    - Medicine (Box 76.1, Folder 9)
    - Migration charts (Box 76.1, Folder 10)
    - Migration Charts Ogden, Utah Politics, circa 1920 (Box 76.1, Folder 11)
      (American Legion, Bob Major See File on "Biography" -Box 33)
    - Politics, 1953-5 (Box 76.1, Folder 12)
    - Proletarian Literature -- (Box 76.1, Folder 13)
    - Psychological criticism -- (Box 76.1, Folder 14)
    - Public Health Source (Box 76.2, Folder 1)
    - Publishing (Box 76.2, Folder 2)
    - Rodeos -- (Box 76.2, Folder 3)
    - Sacco Vanzetti (forWe Accept With Pleasure) (Box 76.2, Folder 4)
    - Science (Box 76.2, Folder 5)
    - Spiral Press (Box 76.2, Folder 6)